자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
지금 뭐 하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
타이어가 펑크 났네요
믿어져요?
Flat tire.
Can you believe it?
아뇨. 못 믿겠군요
Uh, no, I can't.
이건 당신 차가 아니잖아요
It's not your car.
지금 뭐 하는 거요?
What are you doing?
경찰한테 이 일을
처리하게 하려고요
We'll let the cops sort this out.
조언해 달라고 나한테
돈을 지불하고 있잖아요, 맞죠?
You're paying me for my advice, right?
그럼, 차입 자본을 모두 써요
Well, leverage everything.
빚 좀 지는 거는 걱정 말고요
Don't be afraid of a little debt.
로니!
Ronnie!
누구 없어요?
Hello?
친구 사이에 7백만 달러가
뭐가 대수인가요?
What's seven million bucks
between friends?
아, 신호가 잘 안 잡히네요
지금 주차장이거든요
Hey, I'm, I'm losing you.
I'm in the garage.
좋아요. 오늘 밤에 전화할게요
Right, I'll call you tonight.
뒤돌아보지 마
Don't turn around.
- 헉, 당신, 당신 누구요?
- 내 말 못 들었어?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Hear what I said?
- 네, 들었어요
- 그대로 가만히 있어
- Yeah, yes.
- Stay that way.
- 차 열쇠 여기 있어요
- 난 차가 필요한 게 아니야, 켐프
- Take my keys.
- I don't want your car, Kemp.
손 이리 내
Give me your hand.
- 내 손 말이오?
- 그래
My hand? / Yeah.
그쪽 손 말고, 반대쪽 손
Not that hand, the other one.
안 돼! 안 돼!
No! No!
좋은 하루 되시구려, 켐프 씨!
Have a nice day, Mr. Kemp!
MONK Season 4 Epi. 4
Mr. Monk Goes to the Office
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
변은영(yeap77@nate.com)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/07/29
그 경기 봤어?
선수들이 꼭 몽유병 환자 같더라고!
Did you see that game?
Those guys were just sleepwalking!
제대로 된 러닝백이 필요해
We need a real running back.
- 발로우는 완전히 퇴물이 됐어
- 아멘
Barlow's done.
He's all washed up. / Amen.
- Mr. Monk Goes to the Office -
저 사람들 미식축구에 대한 얘기를
하고 있네요. 거기에 관한 거 있는데...
They're talking about football.
I have that one.
카드 줘 봐요
Give me the cards.
몽크 씨, 당신한테는 카드가 필요 없어요
Mr. Monk, you don't need the cards.
그냥 가서 말 걸라고요
Just go talk to them.
당신은 재미있는 사람이에요
You are an interesting person.
그냥 평소 하던 대로 할 수 없어요?
Can't you just be yourself?
그냥 카드 줘 봐요
Give me the cards.
날씨, 정치
Weather, politics,
영화, 욕...
movies, swearwords...
- 욕이요?
- 그거 보지 마요
- Swearwords?
- Don't you look at that one.
여기 있군. 미식축구
Here it is, football.
좋아, 그렇군
Okay, I got it.
준비됐어요
I got it.
안녕하세요
Hey.
하, 몽크 씨 왔네요
Hah, Monk is here.
이제 모두 집에 가도 되겠군
I guess we can all go home now.
당신들 지금
어젯밤 경기 얘기하는 거예요?
You guys talking
about last night's game?
샌프란시스코 포티나이너스가
27대 21로 졌지요
San Francisco 49ers
lost 27 points to 21 points.
네, 우리도 압니다
Yes, we know.
그런데 4쿼터는 진짜
끔찍하더군요
That was a hell of
a fourth quarter, though.
완전히 실책투성이었어요
It was the turnovers.
실책들은 절대 머리에서 떠나질 않죠
They always come back to haunt you.
네, 나도 지금 래테이가 그 압박을
못 견뎌 한다는 걸 지적하고 있었어요
Yeah, I was just saying Rattay
can't handle the pressure.
그래서 말인데, 왜 래테이를
교체하지 않았을까요?
I mean, why didn't they
take him out?
실례합니다
Excuse me.
쿼터백인 팀 래테이에 대한 건
사실이에요
That's true about Tim Rattay,
the quarterback.
하지만 잊지 말아요
But don't forget,
래테이는 최근 5번의 홈경기에서
4번을 승리로 이끌었다고요
he won four out of
his last five home games.
그런데 어제 경기는
휴스턴에서 열렸는데요, 몽크 씨
But they were playing in Houston, Monk.
당신들 욕 몇 가지 들어볼래요?
You guys wanna hear some swearwords?
이봐, 몽크
Hey, Monk.
지금 뭐 하는 건가?
What are you doing?
그냥 지역 미식축구 팀에 대해
얘기하고 있었어요
We're just talking about
the local football franchise.
아, 나이너스 팀 말이군
All right. The niners.
그게 아니죠
샌프란시스코 포티나이너스예요
Heh, no.
The San Francisco 49ers.
따라와. 시체는 이쪽에 있네
Come on. Body's over here.
네, 알겠어요. 나머지 얘기는
가는 길에 하도록 하죠
Yeah, sure.
I'll catch you guys on the flipside.
또 그러는군요
There it is.
등 뒤로 들려오는 비웃음을
들을 때가 제일 끔찍해요
Hearing them laugh as I walk away.
That's the worst part.
- 몽크 씨, 당신을 비웃는 게 아녜요
- 아뇨. 맞아요
- Mr. Monk, they're not laughing at you.
- Yeah, right.
첫 번째 희생자는 주차장 관리인으로
이름이 로니, 어...
Victim A, the garage attendant.
His name was Ronnie, uh...
- 로날드 쉘턴입니다
- 쉘턴
Ronald Shelton. / Shelton.
이 친구는 여기서 2년 동안 일했어요
Guy worked here for 2 years.
45구경으로 가슴에
두 발 맞았습니다
Shot twice in the chest with a .45.
탄피는 회수했고요
We recovered the shells.
탕, 탕, 그 친구는 여기서 죽었네
Bang, bang, he's dead here.
그러고 나서 범인은 쉘턴의 시체를
이리로 끌고 와서
The shooter then drags
Shelton's body this way
이 트럭 밑으로 굴려 놨어
and rolls him under this truck.
그리고 계속해서 주차장에서
기다렸다네
Then he hangs out here
in the garage and waits.
- 뭘요?
- 두 번째 희생자 워렌 켐프를요
- For what?
- For victim B, Warren Kemp.
그는 주차장에 7시 30분에 들어와서
He enters the garage at 7:30.
자기 차로 가는 중이었죠
Heads for his car.
와우, 멋진데요
Wow. Sweet ride.
네. 나도 이런 거 하나를
살까 생각 중이에요
Yeah, I'm thinking of
getting one of these myself.
랜디, 꿈 깨게
Meanwhile, back on Earth, the killer
forces Kemp over to the car,
범인은 켐프를
강제로 차로 데려온 뒤에
총으로 위협해서 그 친구 손을
차 문에 넣고...
at gunpoint, makes him put
his hand in the car door...
and breaks it.
부러뜨렸다네
범인이 첫 번째 남자를 죽이고
기다렸는데...
He killed the first guy,
then waited around...
두 번째 남자는 겨우
손만 부러뜨렸다고요?
but then only breaks
the second guy's hand?
오른손이었다네, 왼손이 아니라
His right hand, not his left hand.
범인이 그걸 매우
구체적으로 요구했다는군
He was very specific about that.
- 그러고는 도망갔다네
- 켐프가 그 사람을 알아보던가요?
- And then he takes off.
- Kemp recognize him?
아니. 범인 얼굴을 못 봤다는군
No. He didn't see his face.
- 강도인가요?
- 아닐세
Robbery? / Nope.
왜 하필 손일까요?
Why his hand?
- 저 사람이 연주자나 외과 의사인가요?
- 잘나가는 주식 분석가로
- Is he a musician or a surgeon?
- He's a big-time stock analyst.
위층의 금융 기관 중
하나에서 근무합니다
He works at one of
the financial places upstairs.
알다시피, 회사를 매점하고
합병하는 일이죠
You know, buyouts and mergers.
순전히 돈놀이하는 거지
Money for nothing.
저 사람이 몽크인가요?
Is that Monk?
네. 뭐 일종의 셜록 홈즈 같은
천재라고 할 수 있죠
Yeah. He's supposed to be some kind
of genius, like Sherlock Holmes.
옆의 여자는 누구인가요?
Who's the girl?
어, 조수예요. 이름이
나탈리인가 그랬던 거 같아요
Uh, his assistant, Natalie something.
뭐 발견한 거 있나?
What you got?
음, 이 타이어 공구는
미터로 표시되어 있는데
Well, this tire iron is metric.
이 차에 안 맞아요
It doesn't fit this car.
사실, 여기 있는 모든 차는
미국에서 만들어진 거예요
In fact, all the cars down here
are American made.
제 생각엔 범인이 타이어를 교체하는
척하기 위해 이걸 가져온 거 같아요
I think the killer brought this down
to pretend to change a tire.
아마 수입 차를 운전하는 사람이겠군요
좋아요, 다른 사항은요?
Probably drives an import.
Good, what else?
핀셋 좀 줘요
음, 심적으로 불안한 사람인가 봐요
Tweezers.
Well, he's insecure.
항상 본래 모습보다 강인하게 행동해서
강한 인상을 주려고 노력하고요
He's always trying to impress people.
- Act tougher than he is.
- How do you know that?
그걸 어떻게 아시죠?
이걸 씹고 있었거든요
He was chewing on this.
이쑤시개군요
Toothpick.
- 꼭 그렇다는 건 아니에요
- 경감님
It's not conclusive. / Captain.
단지 가설일 뿐이죠
틀릴 수도, 틀릴 수도 있어요
Just a theory.
Could, could be wrong.
- 어, 켐프는 좀 어떤가?
- 아직 치료를 더 해야겠어요
- Yeah? How's Kemp?
- I can't release him yet.
몇 가지 엑스레이 검사를 위해
병원으로 데려갈 겁니다
Gotta get him back to the hospital
for some X-rays.
경감님께 메시지를 전해 달라는데
But he gave me a message.
He said to tell you
내일 아침 열 시에 자기 사무실에서
몽크 씨를 만나고 싶다는군요
that he can meet Mr. Monk tomorrow
morning at his office,10 o'clock.
당신도 만나고 싶대요
He says he hopes to see you too.
누구, 나 말이에요?
Who, me?
프로스 금융 서비스
Pross
Financial Services
네, 몽크 씨
Yes, Mr. Monk.
켐프 씨는 이쪽 끝으로 가서
왼쪽으로 가면 있어요
He's all the way to the end
and on the left.
안녕하세요, 켐프 씨를 만나러 온
에이드리안 몽크라고 하는데요
Hi, Adrian Monk for Mr. Kemp.
지금 전화로 회의 중이시니
He's on a conference call.
- 여기 잠깐 앉아 계세요
- 고맙습니다
- You can have a seat.
- Thanks.
저도 이런 곳에서 일한 적이 있었는데
2주 정도밖에 못 버텼어요
I used to work in a place like this.
I lasted about two weeks.
날마다 똑같은 일을 하거든요
You do the same thing every day.
똑같은 일이라
The same thing.
조금 지나면 자신이 마치
숫자처럼 느껴지죠
After a while, you begin
to feel like a number.
- 숫자요?
- 다른 모든 사람들과 똑같아져요
- A number.
- You're just like everybody else.
- 모든 사람들이라...
- 기본적으로 일벌이 되는 거죠
- Everybody else.
- You're basically a drone.
일벌이요?
A drone?
만날 준비가 되셨대요
He's ready for you.
따라오세요
If you'll follow me.
몽크 씨
Mr. Monk.
워렌 켐프입니다
Warren Kemp.
- 악수를 못해 죄송합니다
- 오, 괜찮습니다
- Forgive me for not shaking hands.
- Oh, I don't mind.
당신이 나탈리 맞죠?
It's Natalie, right?
몽크 씨의 충직한 여비서
His gal Friday.
뭐 그렇다고 할 수 있죠
손은 어떠세요?
Something like that.
How's the hand?
뼈 아홉 개가 부러졌대요
Nine broken bones.
하나 더해서 10개가
부러졌으면 짝수가 됐을 텐데요
One more would have been an even 10.
실망하셨다는 말로 들리네요, 몽크 씨
Well, you sound disappointed, Mr. Monk.
지금 말해봐야 너무 늦었네요
Well, it's too late now.
- 사무실 멋진데요
- 그래요?
Nice digs.
Yeah?
"쌀 때 사고, 비쌀 때 팔아라"란 말이
정말 효과가 있나 봐요, 그렇죠?
So this "buy low, sell high"
stuff really works, huh?
- 네, 그런가 봐요
- 와우
- Well, apparently.
- Wow.
전화기 옆에 있는 장치는 뭔가요?
What's that, head to the phone?
도청 방지용 목소리 변환기예요
It's a voice scrambler.
제가 취급하는 매매 중 일부는
매우 보안을 요하는 것이라서요
Some of the transactions
I handle are top secret.
보안 업체가 2주마다 와서
Security comes through twice a week,
도청기를 제거해 주죠
제임스 본드가 된 거 같다니까요
sweeping for bugs.
I feel like James Bond.
이제 그만 앉으시죠
Please, sit down.
켐프 씨
Mr. Kemp,
범인이 당신 이름을
알고 있었다던데요
I understand that the man
that attacked you knew your name.
- 맞습니다
- 하지만 당신은 모르는 사람이고요
- That's right.
- But you didn't recognize him.
네, 제대로 쳐다보질 못했거든요
No, I never got a good look at him.
목소리는 알아보셨나요?
Did you recognize his voice?
아니요, 유감스럽게도요
No, sorry.
왜 당신의 오른손이 부러지길 원했는지
짐작 가는 거라도 있으세요?
Any idea why somebody would wanna
break your right hand?
혹시 중요한 계약에 서명을
하실 순간이었나요?
Are you about to sign
an important contract?
그건 상관없습니다
여전히 서명할 수 있거든요
It would matter.
I can still sign my name.
그러니까 "X" 표시만 해도
여전히 법적으로 인정되거든요
I mean, if I make an "X,"
it would still be legal.
- 그런데 가구를 옮기셨나요?
- 네, 맞아요!
So you've been moving furniture?
That's right!
I just hired a new decorator.
얼마 전에 새 인테리어 업자를 고용했는데
풍수지리 신봉자거든요
Some Feng Shui nut.
그 여자 말로는 책상이
문을 향하도록 배치되면
She says if my desk faces the door,
새로운 기회들이 생겨날 거라고 했어요
it would open me up to new opportunities.
혹시 뭔가 알고 있었나 봐요
Maybe she was on to something.
- 그런데 가구 옮긴 걸 어떻게 아셨어요?
- 카펫 자국요
- How did you know about the furniture?
- Impressions in the rug.
책상이 저기 있었던 것 같네요
The desk used to be there.
굉장하네요
That's pretty good.
당신이 꼭 탐정 같은데요
Who's the detective here?
켐프 씨, 어...
Mr. Kemp, uh...
저한테 몇 가지 물어볼 게 있다고
경감님이 그러시던데요
Captain said that you
wanted to ask me some questions.
맞아요, 몽크 씨
Mr. Monk, I'll admit it.
전 살해당할까 봐 두려워요
왜냐면 범인이 제 이름을 알고 있으니까요
I'm scared to death.
I mean, this creep knew my name.
범인은 제 주위에 있을 수도 있잖아요
It could be someone close to me.
맞아요 / 경찰이 빌딩 주위를
감시한다고는 했지만
I agree. / And the police have
the building staked out but...
전 여기서 일해줄 사람이 필요해요
I need someone working here.
비밀리에 사건을 해결하기 위해서요
Undercover, trying to figure it out.
전 당신을 신뢰하고
당신의 판단을 믿어요
I trust you.
I trust your judgment.
- 누구 추천해줄 만한 사람 없나요?
- 제가 할게요
- Can you recommend someone?
- I'll do it.
- 뭐라고요?
- 제가 할게요
- What?
- I'll do it.
정말 감사합니다
벌써 마음이 한결 가벼워지네요
Oh, thank you.
I feel better already.
You can start tomorrow.
내일부터 시작하셔도 됩니다
아니, 안 돼요
당신이 잘 몰라서 그래요
No, no, no. You don't understand.
몽크 씨는 사무실에서 근무 못해요
He can't work in an office.
여기엔 사람들이 있거든요
There are, there are people here.
아니에요. 괜찮으실 거예요
Nah, nah, he'll be fine.
시카고에서 제가 데리고 온
투자 분석가라고 말해둘게요
I'll say you're an investment analyst
I'm bringing in from Chicago.
- 시카고
- 그냥 바쁜 척하시면 됩니다
- Chicago.
- All you have to do is look busy.
교정 볼 자료를 몇 개 드릴게요
I'll give you some reports to collate.
당신도 들었죠?
Did you hear that?
내가 교정을 보게 됐다고요
I'm gonna be collating.
시카고요?
나한테는 너무 추운 곳이에요
So you from chicago?
It's too cold for me.
여기 날씨도 그리 좋지는 않지만요
Not that the weather here is much better.
여기가 식당인데 자판기 음식을
먹어도 죽지는 않을 거예요
The kitchenette. Some of the food
in that machine is still edible.
사무실 유머군요
마음에 들어요
Office humor.
I love it.
영업부는 저쪽이고
여기는 회계 부서예요
Sales department's down there.
This is accounting.
사무실 전체 인테리어를
다시 하는 중이죠
We're redecorating the whole office.
담배 피세요?
Do you smoke?
혹시 피우신다면 휴게실의 화재경보기가
보통 고장 나 있다는 걸 알아두세요
If you do, the smoke detector
in the break room's usually broken,
- 무슨 말인지 아시겠죠?
- 그거 화재의 위험이 있는 거 아닌가요?
- if you know what I mean.
- Isn't that kind of a fire hazard?
화재라도 났으면 좋겠어요
I hope so.
운이 좋으면, 이 빌어먹을 사무실이
전부 타 버리겠죠
If we're lucky, this whole
frigging place'll burn down.
이게 당신의 주차증이에요
Here's your parking pass.
지하 주차장에 주차할 때는
미행하는 사람이 없는지 확인하세요
If you park in the garage,
make sure someone walks you downstairs.
- 이틀 전 밤에 문제가 좀 있었거든요
- 아, 저도 그 일에 대해서 들었어요
- We had a problem there two nights ago.
- Oh, I heard about that.
왜 켐프 씨의 손을
부러뜨리고 싶어 했을까요?
Why do you think someone
would wanna break Kemp's hand?
아마 작년 크리스마스 파티 때
켐프 씨의 피아노 연주를 들어서였겠죠
Probably someone who heard him playing
piano at last year's Christmas party.
아, 사무실 유머가 상당하네요
좋아요
Oh, more office humor.
That's good.
여기가 당신 자리예요
This is you.
아주 편안한 자리죠
Home sweet home.
여기가 제 자리라고요?
This is me?
완벽해요
It's perfect.
네, 꿈이 실현된 거죠
Yeah. It's a dream come true.
지금 뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
이분은 에이드리안 몽크 씨예요
This is Adrian Monk.
오늘부터 여기서 근무해요
He's starting here today.
켐프 씨가 이 자리를 내가
써도 된다고 했어요
Mr. Kemp said I could have that cubicle.
- 무슨 차이예요?
- 비상구에 더 가깝단 말이에요
- What's the difference?
- It's closer to the emergency exit.
통계적으로, 좀 더 안전해요
Statistically, it's a little safer.
통계적으로, 당신은
좀 괴상한 사람이에요
Statistically, you're a little nuts.
약 복용치를 2배로 올리고
가서 일이나 하는 게 어때요?
Why don't you double up on your
medication and get back to work?
그냥 무시해 버려요
Ignore him.
저 사람은 좀...
He's a little...
이제 모든 게 다 됐어요
So we're all set.
다른 질문 사항이 생기면
주저하지 말고 다른 사람한테 물어 보세요
If you have any other questions,
don't hesitate to ask somebody else.
다른 사람이라...
좋았어
Somebody else.
I get it.
여기서 너무 열심히 일할
필요는 없습니다
하지만 그러면 좋겠죠
You don't have to be CRAZY
to work here...
But it helps
사내에서 칠튼 핸디를 위해
모금을 하고 있어요
We're taking up a collection
for Chilton Handy.
그 사람의 40번째 생일이거든요
It's his birthday. He's 40.
아, 저는 여기 이제 막 와서요
Oh, I, I just got here.
당신도 여기서 근무하는 거 맞죠?
You work here, right?
대부분 사람들은 10달러를 넣었어요
Most people put in 10 bucks.
나는 20달러 넣었고요
I put in 20.
알았어요, 알았다고요. 그럼
Okay. Okay, then.
여기 있어요
Here you go.
당신이 칠튼이에요?
You're Chilton?
맞아요
That's right.
이제 마흔 살이 됐죠
I'm turning 40.
아, 생일 축하해요
Well, happy birthday.
지난번에 일어난 사건에 대해
어떻게 생각해요?
What do you think about what happened?
켐프 씨한테 일어난 일요?
You mean to Kemp?
음, 좀 이상하지 않아요?
Well, it's pretty strange, huh?
손을 부러뜨리다니
도대체 왜 그랬을까요?
Breaking his hand.
Why would somebody do that?
아마 지난번 직원 평가가
마음에 안 들었나 보죠
Maybe someone didn't like
their last employee evaluation.
경감님, 이게 방금 왔습니다
Captain, this just came in.
앉아서 들어 보시는 게
좋을 거 같네요
I think you better sit down.
그게 뭔데?
What is it?
제 생각엔 경감님이 꼭 자리에
앉으셔야 할 거 같은데요
I really think you ought to sit down, sir.
난 별로 앉고 싶지 않다네, 랜디
무슨 일인가?
I don't wantto sit down, Randy.
What is it?
꽤 큰 겁니다
It's pretty big, sir.
- 뭔가?
- 알겠습니다
- What is it?
- Okay.
경감님, 저는 아까 앉아서
전화를 받았는데
Sir, it's just that when I got
the call, I was sitting down,
제가 앉아 있었다는 게 정말 기뻤어요
and I'm really glad I was.
누가 죽었나?
Somebody die?
누가 다쳤나?
Is anybody hurt?
방금 증권 거래 위원회와 통화를 했는데
I just got off the phone with the SEC.
내부 거래법 위반으로
워렌 켐프 씨를 조사 중이래요
They're investigating
Warren Kemp for insider trading.
- 그게 다인가?
- 분명히 정보가 새고 있는데
- Is that it?
- There's definitely a leak.
증권 거래 위원회에서는 그걸
회사 내부인의 소행으로 보고 있어요
And they're pretty sure that
it's coming from inside the firm.
한 가지 가설은 워렌 켐프 씨가
스스로 한 거라는 거고요
One theory is that
it's Warren Kemp himself.
그런데 켐프 씨가
마음을 고쳐먹으려 하자
But he was having second thoughts,
범인이 하던 대로 하라는
경고의 의미로 손을 부러뜨린 겁니다
so our guy breaks his hand
as a warning to keep him in line.
그게 끝인가?
And that's it?
네, 경감님
Yes, sir.
그것 때문에 앉으라고 한 거야?
And you had me sit down for that?
아닙니다
No.
그 이유 말고도 좀 피곤해
보이시는 거 같았거든요
No, it wasn't just that.
I mean, you looked a little bit tired.
제 전화 소리인가요?
Is that my phone?
자네 전화라고?
Your phone?
디셔입니다. 아, 예...
Disher. Uh-huh.
네. 저 전화 좀 받겠습니다, 경감님
Yeah. I gotta take this, sir.
네, 아니, 아니요
지금 가는 중입니다
Yeah, no, no, no. I'm on my way.
네, 아니에요. 확실해요
Right, no. Absolutely.
휴, 이런
Uh, yeah.
에이드리안, 모든 파일 정리함을
재정리 할 필요는 정말 없는데요
Adrian, really, you don't have
to reorganize the whole filing room.
사실 벌써 했어요
Actually, I did.
그리고 제 사무실을
정리해줘서 너무 고마워요
And thanks again for cleaning my office.
제 책상이 아닌 거 같다니까요
I can see my desk again.
여자였으면 훌륭한 아내가
됐을 거예요
You're gonna make somebody
a wonderful wife.
아, 그렉, 이거
분기별 판매 보고서인데
Oh, Greg, here's
that quarterly sales report.
몇 가지 오타와 문법적 오류가 있어서
내가 다시 타이핑했어요
I found a few typos and
grammatical errors, so I retyped it.
전부 다시 타이핑했다고요?
당신은 제 구세주예요
Retyped the whole thing?
You're my hero.
그럼 식사는 어디서 할까요?
So where are we eating?
그냥 브로드웨이 그릴에 가요
Let's just go to the Broadway grill.
바로 옆 건물에 있거든요
It's right across the courtyard.
어서 와요, 에이드리안
Come on, Adrian.
어서 와요, 아넷트
Come on, Annette.
저는 다음에 오는 걸 탈게요
I'll get the next one.
- 여기 자리 많아요
- 그냥 기다릴게요
- There's plenty of room here.
- I'd rather wait.
- 당신은 충분히 탈 수 있어요
- 겨우 두 층이에요
- You could fit right here.
- It's only two floors.
아녜요. 나는, 나는 괜찮아요
Okay, I'm, I'm fine.
우리는 전염병 환자가 아니에요
We're not contagious.
당신들이 전염병 환자가 아닌 거 알아요
I know you're not contagious.
다음 엘리베이터 타고 갈게요
I'll take the next one.
몽크 씨, 당신 걱정 많이 했어요
Mr. Monk, I was worried about you.
- 어땠어요?
- 음, 좋아요. 잘 되고 있어요
- How's it going?
- Um, fine. It's going good.
오, 다행이네요
Oh, good.
좋아요. 저 지금
막 경감님과 얘기했는데
All right, I just talked to the captain.
증권 거래 위원회에서
이 회사를 조사하고 있대요
The SEC is investigating this place.
케이먼 제도에 있는
은행 계좌 하나를 알아냈는데
They have a bank account
in the Cayman islands.
누군가가 내부 정보를 이용해서
수백만 달러를 벌고 있대요 / 네
Somebody's making millions
based on insider information. / Yeah.
심지어 워렌 켐프 씨가 공모자라는
말도 안 되는 의심을 하고 있대요
They even have this crazy theory
that Warren Kemp's involved.
제정신들이 아닌 거 같죠?
Isn't that insane?
- 가요. 점심 먹으면서 계속 얘기해요
- 오, 안 돼요
- Come on, let's talk about it at lunch.
- Oh, I can't.
- 지금 동료들 만나러 갈 거거든요
- 동료 누구요?
- I'm meeting the gang.
- What gang?
난 동료가 생겼어요. 내가 그 일원이
됐는데 지금 날 기다리고 있어요
I have a gang. I'm in the gang.
They're waiting for me.
잠깐만요. 무슨 말을 하고 있는 거예요?
Wait, what are you talking about?
나탈리, 그 사람들은 나를 좋아해요
Natalie, they like me.
카드 몇 장을 가지고 왔는데
그걸 쓸 필요도 없었다고요
I brought some cards along.
I haven't had to use them.
아무도 나를 비웃지 않아요
가봐야겠어요
Nobody's laughing at me.
I gotta go.
나중에 얘기해요
I'll talk to you later.
몽크 씨, 수사는 어때요?
단서가 좀 나왔나요?
Mr. Monk, how's the case coming?
Any leads?
아직 구체적인 건 없어요
Nothing concrete.
지금은 가봐야 해서 말씀 못 드리겠네요
동료들이 나를 기다리고 있거든요
I can't talk right now. I gotta go.
The gang is waiting for me.
켐프 씨
Mr. Kemp.
그냥 워렌이라고 불러주세요
Warren, please.
여긴 어쩐 일이에요?
So what are you doing here?
몽크 씨와 점심 먹으려고 왔는데
다른 약속이 있다네요
I was going to take Mr. Monk to lunch,
but he had other plans.
그럼 이제 한가하겠군요
So you're free.
네
Yeah.
여기 있습니다
Here you go.
- 오, 고마워요, 파멜라
- 맛있게 드세요
- Oh, thank you, Pamela.
- Dig in.
아주 맛있네요
That was very good.
맛있어요
Delicious.
그런데...
So...
함께 일하면서 사귀는 게
어렵지는 않나요?
Is it hard to work together
and, and be in a relationship?
무슨? / 무슨 얘기예요?
What? / What?
두 분 사귀시잖아요, 맞죠?
The two of you are having a thing, right?
왜 그런 말을 하는 거예요?
Why do you say that?
음, 당신 셔츠의 칼라 끝부분에
구멍이 있는데요
Well, your shirt, there's
a hole on the end of your collar.
그렉이 어제 그 셔츠를
입고 있었거든요
Greg was wearing that same shirt yesterday.
또, 같은 샴푸와
같은 탈취제를 사용하고 있고요
Plus, you're using the same shampoo
and the same deodorant.
게다가 오늘, 그렉이 당신 우산을
가지고 출근했죠
And today, Greg walked in
with your umbrella.
형사가 되지 그랬어요
You should be a detective.
아니, 아니에요. 난 형사 못해요
절대 못할 거예요
No, no, I couldn't be a detective.
I could never be a detective.
형사들은 외롭고 또...
매우 고독하고 슬퍼요
They're lonely.They're,
they're very lonely and sad.
형사들에겐 동료가 없어요
They don't have a gang.
사무실에서 일하는 동료가요
A gang from the office.
그럼 이게 백만장자들이
점심을 먹는 방법인가요?
So this is how millionaires do lunch, huh?
아, 이건 백만장자들이
백만장자가 되는 방법이죠
Ah, this is how millionaires
become millionaires.
이혼하고 스트레스에 시달리고
데이트도 못하고요
And divorced and stressed out
and dateless.
어머, 여기서 우리 보스가 보이네요
Oh, I can see my boss from here.
보스가 웃고 있어요
He's laughing.
못 알아보겠는데요
I hardly recognize him.
저거 당신 거예요?
Is that yours?
아름다운데요
That's beautiful.
그래요? 난 기억이 안 나는데요
Is it? I don't remember.
그걸 2년 동안 본 적이 없어요
I haven't seen it in two years.
워렌, 사무실을 벗어나서
외출 좀 해야겠네요
Warren, we gotta get you
out of this office.
지난번에 버몬트 주에 갔다가
감옥에 갇혔었어요
The last time I was in Vermont,
I was in jail.
진짜요? / 네
What? / Yeah.
술집에서 한 남자를 때렸죠
내 친구한테 계속 집적거려서
I hit a guy in a bar.
He wouldn't leave my friend alone.
그 남자를 창문으로
밀쳐버렸거든요
So I just sort of shoved
him through the window.
혹시 지금 날 유혹하고 있는 거라면
If you're trying to turn me on here,
유혹이 잘 통하고 있어요
it's working.
맙소사
Oh, my god.
내가 당신한테 이런 얘기를
했다는 게 믿어지지 않아요
I can't believe I just told you that.
내가 체포됐었다는 얘기는
절대 하면 안 돼요. 알겠죠?
You cannot tell anyone
I've been arrested, okay?
몽크 씨는 물론이고 내 딸 줄리한테는
절대로요, 걔가 알게 되면...
Mr. Monk, my god, Julie, my daughter.
If she knew, please.
- 약속해요
- 그럼요. 약속해요
- You have to promise me.
- Oh, no, I promise.
좋아요 / 이제 당신이 약속을 해줘요
Okay. / Now you have to promise me
something.
네
Yes.
나한테 계속 전화해서 저 오두막이
얼마나 멋진지 상기시켜 줘요
That you'll keep calling and
reminding me how pretty that cabin is.
내가 당신을 데리고 그 오두막을
직접 보여줄 때까지요
Until I can take you up there
and show it to you myself.
좋아요
Okay.
이봐요, 셜록 홈즈
Hey, Sherlock Holmes.
이리 와봐요
Come here.
지금 누가 이걸 했는지
알아맞추려고 하고 있어요
We're trying to figure out who did this.
- 이건 백인의 엉덩이군요
- 네
- This is a human caucasian buttocks.
- Yeah.
네, 알고 있어요
Yeah, we know.
그런데 어떤 백인의 엉덩이일까요?
But whose caucasian buttocks?
칠튼 것일 거야
Gotta be Chilton.
지옥에나 가버려
Go to hell.
아니요, 이 사람은 벤이에요
Uh, no, this is Ben.
정말 어른다운 짓이네요, 벤!
Real mature, Ben!
어떻게 알았어요?
How'd you know?
음, 호치키스 철심이 안쪽이 아니라
바깥쪽으로 나 있는데
Well, the staples go out, not in.
사무실용 호치키스 중에 저런 식으로
설정된 건 벤의 것밖에 없어요
Ben's is the only stapler
in the office set to do that.
지금 뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
이걸 떼어 내는 거예요
Taking this down.
게임은 끝났잖아요
몰수 게임이라고요
The tournament's over.
You guys forfeit.
누가 그래요? 우리는 아직
몰수패를 안 당했다고요
Who said that?
We don't forfeit anything.
볼링 대회가 있는데
결승전이 오늘 밤에 열려요
It's our bowling league.
The finals are tonight.
좋아요, 그렇다고 치죠
볼링장에서 봅시다
Okay, fine.
I'll see you there.
그러나 톡톡히 망신당하게 될 거요
But you're just gonna
embarrass yourselves.
보통 때보다 더 심하게요
Even worse than usual.
당신들 팀에서 켐프 씨가 유일하게
좀 하는 볼링 선수였으니까요
Mr. Kemp was the only bowler
you had that didn't suck.
켐프 씨가 볼링을 해요?
Mr. Kemp bowls?
더 이상은 아니에요
Not anymore.
부러진 손으로는 할 수 없잖아요
Not with a busted hand.
저 재수없는 녀석 말이 옳아요
Creep is right.
우리는 완패당할 거예요
We're gonna get slaughtered.
수요일 밤
사내 볼링 대회
Wednesday Nights
Inter-Office Bowling
볼링이라
Bowling.
생각했던 것보다 소리가 크네요
It's louder than I thought it would be.
정말 저 남자가 사람을
죽였다고 생각해요?
Do you really think
that guy killed somebody
게다가 겨우 볼링 대회 우승을 위해
켐프 씨의 손을 부러뜨렸다는 거예요?
and broke Warren Kemp's
hand just to win a bowling trophy?
이상하다는 거 아는데
저 사람 좀 봐요
I know it's crazy, but look at him.
완전히 강박 관념에
사로잡혀 있잖아요
He's completely obsessed.
나와 달리 나쁜 의미로요
And not in a good way, like me.
Plus, he'sa toothpick chewer.
또, 이쑤시개도 씹어요
월요일 밤에 저 사람 알리바이는
뭔데요? /좋은 질문이에요
- Does he have an alibi for Monday night?
- Good question.
- 에이드리안, 당신 차례예요
- 나요?
- Adrian, you're up.
- Me?
켐프 씨의 빈자리를
채워줄 사람이 필요해요
We need someone to fill in for Mr. Kemp.
그게 아니면 왜 우리가
당신보고 와 달라고 했겠어요?
Why do you think we asked you to come?
왜냐면 나도 동료 중 한 사람이니까요
Because I'm one of the gang.
당신 셔츠예요
공이나 찾아와요
Here's your shirt.
Find a ball.
좋아요 / 네
All right. / Yeah.
잘 찾아봐요
Good eye, good eye.
당신 공을 찾아봐요
Find your ball.
스텝을 보니 잘 칠 거 같군요
Walk's as good as a hit.
여기요
Here.
가져가요, 가져가요
Take it, take it, take it.
좋았어 / 오, 예!
All right. / Oh, yeah!
하나만 더 쓰러뜨렸어도
짝수인 10이 됐을 거예요
One more, it would
have been an even 10.
오, 한 번 더 기회가 있어요
두 번 치는 거예요
Oh, you get another chance.
You get two balls.
정말요?
Really?
가서 해요
Go get it.
- 왜 이리 굼떠요
- 내가...
You're so slow. / I'm...
이봐요, 혹시 월요일 밤에 TV에서 하는
그 코미디 쇼 봤어요?
Hey, did you watch that comedy
show on TV Monday night?
뭐라고요?
What?
아, 항상 싸우는
가족에 대한 거였는데
Oh, it was about this family
that argued all the time,
아버지가 항상 틀리죠
and the father was always wrong.
시청자들 웃음소리가 들렸을 테니
You could hear the audience laugh.
당신도 그게 재밌었다는 걸 알았겠죠
So you knew it was funny.
난 못 봤어요
I missed it.
어디에 있었는데요?
Where were you...
- 뭐라고요?
- 월요일 밤에 외출했었나요?
- Pardon me?
- Monday night, did you go out?
당신 경찰이에요?
Are you a cop?
아니요 / 그럼 당신한테
얘기할 필요가 없잖아요
No. / Then I don't have
to talk to you, do I?
그런데 에이드리안과
같이 있는 여자는 누구야?
So who's the girl with Adrian?
그 이메일 못 받았어?
Didn't you get that e-mail?
누가 그녀에 대해서 전체 사무실에
메일을 보냈더라고
Somebody's been sending messages
to the whole office about her.
이름은 나탈리인가 그랬어
지금 켐프 씨한테 작업 걸고 있다던데
Her name's Natalie something.
She's been hitting on Mr. Kemp.
농담하는 거지!
You're kidding!
이것도 있어
And get this.
저 여자는 수감된 적도 있어
She's done time.
버몬트 주에서 한 남자를
거의 죽일 뻔했다던데
She almost killed a guy in Vermont.
고마워요
Thanks.
여보세요 / 모든 사람이
버몬트 주에 대해 알고 있어요, 워렌
Hello. / Everybody knows
about Vermont, Warren.
사람들이 전부 그 얘길 하고 있어요
비밀로 해 달라고 했잖아요!
They're all talking about it.
I told you that in confidence!
나탈리, 난 아무한테도
말하지 않았어요, 맹세한다고요
Natalie, I didn't tell anybody, I swear.
음, 누군가가 사무실 전체에
이메일을 보냈다는데
Well, somebody's e-mailing
your whole office,
당신 말고는 아는 사람이 없잖아요
and nobody but you knew about it.
- 나탈리, 날 믿어야 해요
- 내가 죽으면 그러죠
- Natalie, you have to believe me.
- Like hell I do.
- 몽크 씨, 얘기 좀 해요
- 나탈리, 이것 좀 봐요
- Mr. Monk, we need to talk.
- Natalie, look at this.
칠튼은 알리바이가 있어요
그는 월요일 밤에 여기 왔었어요
Chilton has an alibi.
He was here Monday night.
294점을 기록했군요
He bowled a 294.
- 더 생각해 볼 여지가 없네요
- 내 생각엔 켐프 씨가 개입된 거 같아요
- I don't know what to think.
- I think Warren Kemp's involved.
뭐라고요? / 증권 거래 위원회
생각이 맞는 거 같다고요
- What?
- Maybe the SEC was right.
그건 내부인의 소행인데
그 사람이 의심스러워요
That it's an inside job.
Now, I do not trust that guy.
우린 켐프 씨를 마음에
들어한 거 아니었어요? 그것도 많이요
Well, I thought we liked him.
I thought we liked him a lot.
하지만 이젠 아니에요
Well, we don't.
You know what?
그건 그렇고 밖에서 만나요
바람 좀 쐬어야겠어요
I'll just meet you outside.
I gotta get some air.
에이드리안, 우리는
딱 핀 2개를 뒤지고 있어요
Adrian, We're only down two pins.
당신이 핀 3개를 쓰러뜨리면
우리가 이 게임을 이길 수 있어요
If you can roll three,
we can win the game.
문제없어요
No problem.
반칙, 그건 반칙이에요!
Foul, that's a foul!
그런 신발을 신으면 안 돼요
He can't wear those.
길에서 신는 신발을 신고 있는데
그건 규정 위반이라고요
He's wearing street shoes.
They're not regulation.
하지만 이 사람은 게임 내내
이 신발을 신고 했어요
But he's been wearing them
the whole game. / I don't care.
내가 알 바 아니오
정해진 볼링화를 신지 않으면
볼링을 칠 수 없어요
He can't bowl if he's not
wearing regulation footwear.
That's a rule.
그건 규칙이에요
Fine!
We'll just rent him a pair of shoes.
알았어요!
지금 신발을 대여해 올게요
사이즈가 얼마예요?
What size are you?
어, 문제가 있어요
당신이 신발을 대여한다고 말했을 때
Uh, here's the thing.
When you say, "rent a pair,"
다른 사람들이 신었던 볼링화를
대여해 온다는 말인가요?
you're talking about footwear
that other people have already worn?
맞아요
That's right.
내 발에 신으라고요?
On my feet?
저기 문제가 있어요
Here, here's the thing.
I don't like to share anything.
나는 물건을 함께
쓰는 걸 좋아하지 않아요
좋아요. 그냥 새 볼링화를
사도록 하죠
Fine. Let's just buy him a new pair.
상점은 문 닫았어요
자, 어떻게 할 거예요?
Pro shop's closed.
So what's it gonna be?
If he doesn't bowl, you forfeit.
만약 저 사람이 치지 않으면
당신들의 몰수패예요
여기 있어요. 나와 대충
사이즈가 비슷한 거 같군요
Here. We're about the same size.
도대체 뭘 그렇게 쳐다봐요?
What the hell are you looking at?
이건 그냥 신발이에요
They're just shoes.
- 그냥 신어요
- 문제가 있어요
- Just put them on.
- Here's the thing.
알았어요, "문제가 있어요"란 말은 그만해요
Okay, stop saying, "here's the thing."
그냥 딱 20초 동안만 이 신발을 신고
나중에 바로 벗어버려요
Just put on these shoes for 20 seconds.
Then you can take them right off.
20초라... 글쎄요
20 seconds. I don't know.
그럼 몰수패인가요?
So you forfeit?
들어봐요
Listen.
우리는 이 재수없는 녀석을 이기기 위해
5년을 기다려 왔어요
We've been waiting five years
to beat these creeps.
당신이 해야 할 일은
All you have to do is put on Greg's shoes
and roll the freaking ball.
그렉의 신발을 신고
저 빌어먹을 공을 굴리는 거예요
못하겠어요
I can't.
좋았어! 오, 예
Yes! Oh, yeah.
아자! 몰수패다!
우리가 이겼다!
Yes! That's a forfeit!
We win!
몰수패, 몰수패
몰수패, 몰수패, 패배자들
Forfeit, forfeit,
forfeit, forfeit, losers.
하지만 당신은 제정신이 아냐!
But you are!
이봐요, 이봐요
Hey, hey...
뭘 좀 샀어요
I bought some...
볼링화를 샀다고요
I bought some bowling shoes.
그걸 가지고 당신이
할 수 있는 걸 말해 줄게요
I'll tell you what you can do with those.
그건 처음 듣는 말이네
That's a new one.
- 어떻게 생각해요?
- 뭐라고요?
- What do you think?
- I'm sorry?
어떤 게 더 마음에 들어요?
창문과 사무실 전체를 꾸며서
Which one do you like?
I'm doing the windows and all the offices.
모든 사람들의 공간을
밝게 해주고 싶거든요
I'm trying to brighten up
everyone's spaces.
어떤 거요? 이거요?
Which one? This one?
내 생각엔 이게 아주 약간
더 밝은 거 같은데 당신은 어때요?
I think this is just a tad bit
more sunshiny. Don't you think?
네, 매우 환하네요
Yes, it's very sunshiny.
알겠어요
All right.
뭐하는 거예요?
What are you doing?
뭘 원하는 거예요?
What do you want?
좋아요, 아무거나 가져가요
원하는 건 아무거나 다 가져가요
Okay, take anything.
Take anything you want.
그 베개를 원해요?
그 베개 가져가요. 이탈리아제예요
You want that pillow?
Take that pillow. It's Italian.
오, 맙소사
Oh, my god.
그게 무슨 뜻이지, 경위?
What does it mean, lieutenant?
살인자가 매우 지능적이라는
의미 같습니다
I think it means the killer
was very intelligent.
그럼 주차장 사건과 동일인이라는 거군
So it was the same guy as the garage.
네, 그렇게 보입니다
Yeah, it looks like it.
총탄을 회수했는데 45 구경입니다
지금 대조해보고 있습니다
We recovered the bullets, .45 caliber.
They're comparing it now.
뭔가 또 있습니다, 경감님
Something else, too, sir.
꽤 큰 겁니다
It's pretty big.
걱정 마세요, 앉을 필요는 없으십니다
Don't worry, you don't have to sit down.
그러니까, 앉으셔도 된다는 뜻입니다
I mean, you can sit.
- 앉으셔도 되고, 일어서 계셔도 됩니다
- 다른 데 가봐도 되나?
- I mean, sit or stand.
- Can I walk away?
지금 말씀드리겠습니다
I'll just tell you.
희생자는 안젤라 더크스입니다
인테리어 디자이너고요
The victim, Angela Dirks,
she was an interior designer.
최근 송장을 찾아냈는데
We found some recent invoices.
뭐가 나왔는지 맞춰보세요
Guess what?
그녀는 프로스 금융 서비스의
일을 하고 있었어요
She was working for
Pross financial services.
- 같은 회사로군
- 그렇습니다, 경감님
- The same company.
- Yes, sir.
그럼 범인이 보스의 손을 부러뜨리고
So the guy breaks the boss' hand,
4일 뒤에 인테리어 디자이너를
죽였다는 건가?
and then four days later,
he kills the interior decorator?
도대체 저 회사에서
무슨 일이 벌어지고 있는 거야?
What the hell is going on up there?
그런데 디자이너가
살해당한 건 꽤 이상해요
But that's pretty weird
about the decorator getting killed.
무슨 연관성이 있을 거 같은데
어떻게 생각하세요?
There's gotta be a connection,
don't you think?
몽크 씨?
Mr. Monk?
저건 우리 테이블이었어요
That was our table.
나초를 먹었죠
We ate nachos.
당신이 나초를 먹었다고요?
You ate nachos?
아니요
No.
대신 먹는 척을 했죠
But I pretended to.
그 후에, 벤은 그의 하얀 엉덩이의
복사본을 만들었어요
And then later, Ben made
a copy of his caucasian buttocks.
그건 꽤 재미있었어요
Which was very funny.
비록 왜 그런지는 정확히 모르지만요
Although I don't know exactly why.
몽크 씨, 그건 그 사람들 손해예요
정말이에요
Mr. Monk, it's their loss.
Really, it is.
그 사람들은 전부 길 아래편에 있는
중국 식당으로 갔어요
They're all at the Chinese restaurant
down the street.
몰래 빠져나가는 걸 봤죠
I saw them sneaking out.
날 따돌리려고 했던 거예요
So I wouldn't come with them.
어, 그거 뭐예요?
Uh-oh, what is that?
뭐요? / 뭔가, 뭔가가 있어요
머리카락인가요?
What? / There's, there's something,
is that a hair?
어디요?
Where?
아니요, 괜찮아요
그냥 셀러리예요
No, it's okay.
It's just celery.
나탈리
Natalie.
무슨 일이 벌어졌는지 알아낸 거 같아요
I think I know what happened.
- 뭐라고요?
- 사건을 해결했다고요!
- What?
- I solved the case!
- 왜 그렇게 얘기해요?
- 창문 옆에 있는 남자 보여요?
- Why are you talking like that?
- You see that guy by the window?
녹색 재킷 입고 있는 사람요
The guy in the green jacket.
당신 수프에 뭔가 있다고
말했을 때
When I said there was
something in your soup,
저 사람이 반응했어요
he reacted.
자기 수프를 봤다고요
He looked at his soup.
- 양복이요?
- 수프요, 수프!
- His suit?
- His soup, soup!
음, 당신 얘길 들은 거겠죠
Well, maybe he heard you.
아니요, 저 사람은 들은 게 아니에요
No, he couldn't have.
내 입술을 읽은 게 틀림없어요
He must have read my lips.
입술을 읽을 수 있다고요!
He can read lips!
그게 모든 걸 설명해요
That explains everything.
정말요?
It does?
네, 저 사람은 내가 여기 있을 때마다
Yeah, he's been sitting
at that same table
늘 같은 테이블에 있었어요
every time I've been in here.
아마 한 달 전부터
앉아 있었음에 틀림없어요
He must have been sitting there
about a month ago.
언젠가부터 창 밖을 쳐다보다가
At some point, he looked out the window,
뭔가를 본 거죠
and he saw something.
수백만 달러의 가치가 있는 무언가를요
Something worth millions of dollars.
- 그게 뭔데요? 뭘 본 건데요?
- 워렌 켐프 씨를 본 거예요
- What? What did he see?
- He saw Warren Kemp.
그는 계속해서 워렌의
입술을 읽어왔던 거예요!
He's been reading Warren's lips!
저 테이블에서라면 워렌의 사무실을
완벽하게 볼 수 있었어요
From that table.
He has a perfect view into Warren's office.
메인 광섬유라고 불리는 회사예요
It's a company called Maine fiber optics.
한 주당 32.50달러예요
9월 2일 전까지요
$32.50 a share.
Before September 2nd.
매점, 합병 같은 내부 정보는
돈벌이가 될 만하죠
Buyouts, mergers, that kind
of inside information is worth a fortune.
보지 마요! 보지 마요
Don't look! Don't.
우릴 똑바로 쳐다보고 있어요
He's staring right at us.
당신의 빙긋 웃는 모습 때문에
다들 쳐다보는 걸 거예요
I'm sure everyone is,
the way you're grinning. / That's okay.
괜찮아요
저 사람은 그냥 우리가
사랑에 빠진 거라고 생각할 거예요
He'll just think we're in love.
사랑에 빠진 것처럼은커녕
You don't look like you're in love.
마치 산업 재해를 당한
사람 같아 보여요
You look like somebody who's had
some sort of industrial accident.
여기요, 그냥...
Here, just...
난 이해가 안 돼요
왜 워렌의 손을 부러뜨린 거예요?
I don't get it.
Why would he break Warren's hand?
왜냐면 워렌이 지난주에 사무실
인테리어를 다시 했기 때문이에요
Because Warren redecorated
his office last week.
기억나요? 당신이 직접
알아냈잖아요 / 네
Remember?
You noticed it yourself. / Yeah.
책상 위치를 반대로 바꿨는데
He turned his desk around,
그 결과 오른손으로 전화를 받으면
so that when he held the phone
in his right hand,
입이 가려졌던 거예요
he was blocking his mouth.
그래서 어떻게 해서든지 왼손으로
전화를 받게 해야 했던 거예요
Somehow he had to get Warren
to switch hands.
그게 이 사건의 전부인 거예요?
That's what all this is about?
다른 손으로 전화를
받게 하려는 거요?
So he would hold the phone
in the other hand?
디자이너는 왜 죽였을까요?
Why would he kill the decorator?
그녀가 커튼을 달려고
했던 거 생각나요?
She was planning to put
curtains up, remember?
그로 인해 모든 걸 망칠 수도 있거든요
That would have ruined everything.
맙소사
Oh, my god.
그 남자가 이리로 오고 있어요
Here he comes.
저 거울을 보고 내 입술을
읽을 수 있었나 봐요
With this mirror, he could
have been reading my lips.
사건을 해결했다고 생각해요?
Think you figured something out, huh?
같이 밖으로 나가서
그에 대해 얘기해 보는 건 어때요?
What do you say we all take
a walk outside and talk about it?
- 내가 총을 빼앗을게요
- 다 들려요
- I'm gonna grab the gun.
- I can hear you.
난 타고난 청각 장애인이지만
지금은 괜찮아요
I was born deaf, but I'm okay now.
현대 과학 덕분이죠
Modern science.
- 이제 갑시다
- 알았어요. 지금 가요, 간다고요
- Now let's go.
- Okay, okay, we're going, we're going.
그런데 당신 지금
큰 실수를 하고 있는 거예요
But you're making a huge mistake.
이 사람이 누군지 알아요?
Do you know who this man is?
이 사람은...
He's...
좋았어, 움직이지 마!
All right, don't move!
가만히 있어요!
Stay where you are!
걱정 마세요. 괜찮아요
Don't worry. It's okay.
난 한때 경찰이었어요
I used to be a cop.
경감님께 전화할게요
I'm calling the captain.
잠깐, 잠깐 기다려요
Now, wait, wait. Could you,
미스터 웍 식당에 먼저
전화해 줄래요? / 왜요?
- could you first call Mr. Wok's?
- Why?
거기서 동료들이 식사하고 있는데
이 장면을 꼭 보여주고 싶어요
That's where the gang is eating.
I'd really love them to see this.
커튼이 맘에 들어요
I like the curtains.
그냥, 일시적인 거예요
Well, they're temporary.
곧 15층으로 사무실을 옮길 거예요
They're moving me upstairs
to the 15th floor.
훔쳐보는 사람들로부터
멀리 떨어진 곳으로요
Away from prying eyes.
이해해요
Makes sense.
적어도 그 이메일을
누가 썼는지는 알겠어요
At least we know who wrote that e-mail.
우리가 버몬트 주에 대한 걸
이야기할 때
The killer must have been reading our lips
when we talked about going to Vermont.
살인범이 우리 입술을 읽은 게 틀림없어요
그 사람은 자기의 황금 거위가
Guess he didn't want his golden goose
going on vacation with anybody,
누군가와 함께 휴가 가는 게 싫어서
우리를 갈라놓으려 했나 봐요
so he tried to break us up.
저기, 나탈리, 누가 이메일을
썼는지는 중요하지 않아요
Look, Natalie, it doesn't matter
who wrote the e-mail.
난 결론을 중시하는 사람이죠
I'm a bottom line sort of guy.
그런데 결론은...
And the bottom line is...
그 메일은 내가 쓴 게
아니라고 했고 맹세도 했죠
I told you it wasn't me.
I swore to you.
그런데 당신은
나를 안 믿었다는 거예요
And you didn't believe me.
맞아요. 당신 말이 옳아요
You're right, you're right.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
그냥 이 샴페인을 터뜨린 후
못 했던 얘기나 다시 하는 게 어때요?
Can we just pop this open
and pick up where we left off?
이거 비싼 거예요
It's expensive.
버리지 마요
Don't waste it.
어떻게 됐어요?
How'd it go?
여기서 나가요
Let's get out of here.
또 그러는군요
There it is.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)